Daniel Holzschuh

daholz.com 612-716-5945 d.a.holzschuh@gmail.com 1353 6th St E, Minneapolis, MN 55106

About Me

UX designer grounded in a fine arts background with experience in visual design, web development, and working hard on behalf of the user. Constantly driven to learn new skills, lift up team morale, and solve puzzles (UX, jigsaw, or otherwise).

<u>Skills</u>

Figma, Sketch, Axure, Invision, Miro, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, Adobe XD, Blender, Keynote, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Prototypes, Wireframes, Storyboards, UI Design, User Journey Maps, Comparative Analysis, Feature Cards, Usability Tests, Directed Storytelling, Annotated Wireframes, Information Architecture Maps, Kano Method, Heuristic Analysis, Contextual Inquiry, Kanban

Experience

PRIME DIGITAL ACADEMY - UX Support Instructor June 2021 - January 2022

- Provided support to UX program students by coaching through UX client projects and deliverables.
- Assisted instructors with lectures, student questions, and creating assets.
- Critiqued and provided actionable feedback for student portfolios.

SPORTS STAR PHOTOGRAPHY - Photographer February 2021 - June 2022

- Managed multiple concurrent tasks in a loud and fast-paced environment in various locations.
- Learned new skills and work flows on the job quickly, and taught those skills and flows to others.
- Organized large groups of children and adults while taking photos, managing paperwork, and adjusting equipment on the fly.

PRIME DIGITAL ACADEMY - UX Design Student April 2020 - August 2020

Worked on 5 projects for clients - Foodsby, Saint Thomas More Catholic School, MnTech, Talk About Depression, and Prime

- Created wireframes, prototypes, architectural diagrams, conducted user research, synthesized research findings
- Distilled project activities and deliverables into succinct reports and presentations for clients
- Effectively managed time to complete complex projects on tight deadlines
- Collaborated with teams and interviewed test participants remotely

ProCraftr App Self-Defined Project

- Created an interactive prototype for an app that will allow users to manage complex crafting projects
- Utilized Figma to digitize my wireframes, screen flow, and multi-touchpoint strategy user journey map, as well as create the interactive prototype
- Conducted two phases of research discovery research via comparative analysis, directed storytelling, and a feature sorting exercise, and evaluative research via usability tests

Yeeyo's Boutique Group Client Project

- Communicated with local small business owner on behalf of my team of designers to create a multi-touchpoint strategy for adapting her business model for the pandemic.
- Created information architecture, wireframes, and interactive prototype for an e-commerce website.
- Conducted competitive analysis of similar e-commerce businesses, comparative
 analysis of website platforms that would best suit the client's particular needs, and
 conducted a contextual inquiry of the client's physical store.

Education

PRIME DIGITAL ACADEMY
User Experience Design Certification

August 2020

MINNESOTA STATE UNIVERSITY MOORHEAD BFA, Studio Art, Illustration Emphasis, Art History Minor

June 2014